Never forget why you are the church.
Revelation chapter, turn your Bibles to Revelation chapter 10.
Revelation chapter 10.
Um, We've gone through the 6 trumpets so
far up to this point of revelation and the tribulation.
The earth has been changed dramatically.
The trees, the grass, the water sources, the oceans are all
partly destroyed.
The demonic locust army has tortured people for 5
months relentlessly.
The army that looked like, or he was told it was 200
million, has arrived and has gone on a complete killing spree.
The human race has dwindled down to where
at least one out of two people have been killed.
And that's just what we've been told with the numbers that
we've had with the plagues and the judgments.
That's not that's not telling who has died from not
eating or who has died from the other things that happen when
the world goes like it's going.
So it is absolute destruction and death everywhere.
And we've learned that through all of this, the people did not repent.
Those who have survived up to this point, choose to continue in their sin.
Revelation 9, 20 through 21 and the rest of the men, which
would not kill by these plagues, yet repented not of
the works of their hands.
They should not worship devils and idols
of gold and silver and brass and stone and of wood, which neither
can see nor hear nor walk, neither repented they
of their murders, nor of their sorceries, nor their fornications,
nor of their thefts.
In other words, they saw all the things that were going on in the
world, and they thought, okay, I'm gonna continue to walk in sin.
They refused to even acknowledge that all this judgment was because of sin.
rejecting Christ.
And you might say, man, how could anybody?
See that kind of thing and not turn from their sin, their wicked ways.
Let me ask you something.
How can anyone see the goodness of God today and not turn from their wicked ways?
I believe it's harder for us.
It should be harder for us to fathom than in the age of grace,
in the age of God working
like he has worked and us having the full, completed
word of God and the freedom, at least in America,
to be able to do what we do for Christ, and yet we
have so many apathetic, lukewarm, sinful,
professing believers, that should scare us more than this.
But right here, we cannot fathom the state of the world at this point.
However, much is yet to happen.
We move on to a break between the 6 trumpet and the 7th
trumpet, and we're going to be introduced to the angel in the little book.
We're going to read all of chapter 10, okay?
It's just 11 verses.
So if you're there with me, say, read.
Okay?
And I saw another mighty angel, come down
from heaven, clothed with a cloud, and
a rainbow was upon his head, and his face was as it were
the sun, and his feet as pillars of fire.
And he had in his hand a little book open, and he set his right foot upon
the sea, and his left foot on the earth.
And cried with a loud voice as when a lion roareth.
And when he had cried, 7 thunders uttered their voices.
And when the 7 thunders had uttered their voices, I was about to write,
and I heard a voice from heaven saying unto me, seal up those things which
the 7 thunders uttered, and write them not.
And the angel, which I saw, stand upon the scene upon the earth, lifted
up his hand to heaven, and swear by him that liveth forever
and ever who created heaven, and the things that there are,
that therein are, and the earth, and the things that therein
are, and the sea, and the things that are in there, and there
should be time no longer.
That was hard to read, folks.
But in the days of the voice of the 7th angel, when he shall begin,
begin to sound, the mystery of God should be finished as he
hath declared to his servants, the prophets, and the voice, which I heard from
heaven, spake, unto me again and say,
go and take the little book which is open in the hand of the angel, which standeth
upon the sea and upon the earth.
And I went unto the angel and said unto him, give me the little book.
And he said unto me, take it and eat it up.
And it shall make thy belly bitter, but it shall be in thy mouth, sweet as honey.
And I took the little book out of the angel's hand, and I ate it up.
And it was in my mouth, sweetest honey, and as soon as I had
eaten it, my belly was bitter.
And he said unto me, thou must prophesy again.
Before many peoples and nations and tongues and kings.
We see here, there's a break between the 2 trumpets,
the 2nd and last one, the 6th one, the 7th one, to
announce that there's more to come.
Let's pray.
Father, we thank you for this night.
We thank you for your word.
God give me wisdom and discernment to preach your words night and teach it.
And I pray that those have ears to hear, may they hear.
In Jesus' name, pray.
Amen.
Now, there are some unique details about this particular text they're seeing here.
First, we do not know who this angel is, but we can conclude that
is another angel other than the 7 angels that have the trumpets.
Some think this angel to be Jesus Christ.
They would say that this angel and the angel in chapter
8 with the golden censor was Jesus.
There is really no indication that this angel is
Jesus, but in the Old Testament,
We know that Christ appeared frequently as the angel
of Jehovah or the angel of the Lord, but
here this angel could have been just a mighty angel.
Other people think that maybe it's Michael the archangel.
Either way, it is a mighty figure that
God is using to get his will done here.
Second, we see a different approach to the contents revealed to John.
The word revelation itself.
means an unveiling or a disclosure.
In other words, it is a revealing of
something that God wants us to know.
We see this in the very 1st chapter in Revelation
one, one through three, the revelation of Jesus Christ, which God gave him
to show to his bondservants.
The things which must soon take place.
And he sent and communicated it by his angel to his bondservant John.
who testified to the word of God and to the testimony
of Jesus Christ, even to all that he saw.
In other words, it's something that John shared.
Blessed is he who reads.
And those who hear the words of the prophecy, and heed
the things which are written in it, for the time is near.
So God gives John this vision information so
that we can be informed.
That got me thinking as I was putting this together, and I
was talking to Rob me for service.
I'm going to be transparent with you.
Sometimes revelation can seem very redundant and overwhelming.
I mean, if you listen, if you're sitting there thinking, man,
what we talking about, try putting this together, right?
There's so much information.
I'm a detailed kind of person.
I like to go deep.
I like to take my time and it's just there's
so much in this book for us to learn that I'm trying to pick
and choose what God would have me teach in
this series.
But here's the thing.
It could seem like the same stuff over and over again.
There are those parts that we like to think about and speculate about,
and then everything else seems not as important.
It's a very dangerous way to look at scripture to pick
and choose what you care about in scripture.
Think about it.
And I know we've all said it, man.
Anyone ever done a Bible in a year reading?
No?
You should start today.
Is that what you said?
Start today.
There you go.
Yeah, I started one.
Genesis one through 12 is the most red chapters in
scripture, statistically speaking.
They start day one, and then they quit by Genesis 12.
But what I'm trying to say is this.
See, if we look at scripture in
such a way that we pick and choose.
What we're doing is we're not getting the full picture.
And I mention the Bible in a year thing because
what does everyone, anyone has ever done it when you get to Leviticus.
What do you do?
And you roll them eyes, you think, this is gonna be terrible.
And you push through it, right?
Or you just don't tell nobody, and you just go, and you move on, right?
Let me just tell you something.
Leviticus is in there for a reason.
And I'm talking to myself here.
If you don't, if you don't think as a pastor that,
that, you know, in counseling, I use the same scriptures,
it seems like over and over again.
When I talk to someone about Jesus,
I use the same scriptures.
It seems like over and over again.
If we're not careful, we won't get the whole picture.
We'll just get the picture we create.
And that's dangerous.
Can I tell you something?
When you look at it as God's divine, holy, eternal, incorruptible world,
word, then it ceased to become boring
and it becomes alive to you.
Now that takes a lot of discipline.
Amen?
And I'm not telling you that I got it right.
I still roll my eyes when Leviticus comes around when I have my Bible in a year style.
I just do, right?
And there's other books that I do the same thing sometimes, but we got
to understand, God is revealing this for a reason.
Could it be that this is the scheme of the devil?
Think about the world that he controls.
How many movies about the end times, articles written TV shows,
breaking news, rumors of war, and chips, and one
world currency, as if the devil, it's as if the devil has numb
the church to what is to come very soon.
So when we hear about it, we've been so so conditioned to not worry about it.
Well, that's just another rumor.
Well, that's just this.
We have a motto in the church.
Well, they've been saying that Jesus was returning my whole life.
Let me just tell you something.
He's closer today than he's ever been.
I mean, it's just, it's just simple as that.
And tomorrow, if he tarries, we're closer then than we've ever been.
So it does matter, amen?
And we say, well, whatever happens is going to happen anyway.
Well, that mindset might as well you put your Bible down and go home.
But I want to know what God wants me to know.
Does that make sense?
And listen, I say this to you tonight because I have to remind myself of this this morning.
I'm like, God, listen, I'm about to just skip through the rest of these chapters in Revelation.
We going to get to something else and God's like, no, take your time, take it slow.
This is obviously something we need to know.
So anyway, this disclosure of future events would not have been received this
way by John and the early readers.
They would have, if God revealed certain things, they would have
taken heed and to try to know all they could possibly know about it.
That being said, this book is a book of an unveiling,
a disclosure, but look again at what we learn in chapter 10.
Revelation 10, verse 4.
When the 7 thunders had uttered their voices,
I was about to write.
What he's been doing this entire time.
And I heard a voice from heaven saying unto me, seal up
those things which the 7 thunders uttered, and write them not.
Whatever is in these peals of thunder, we are not able to know.
Which is very interesting.
And here's the thing.
I wish I could tell you more.
But we know that it was about things that were to come, so it's going to be
revealed at some point, but in action, rather than words.
Then we get the announcement that the end is coming.
The angel raises his right hand to heaven and swore
by God, there'll be no more delay.
The mystery of God will be finished.
And then we see something that is quite interesting.
The angel takes this little book and tells John to eat it.
It's a little odd, amen?
While it's in his mouth, it'll be sweet, but once his stomach,
it hits his stomach, it's gonna be bitter.
Now what does this mean?
I like how the Bible knowledge commentary explains this.
To John, the word of God was indeed sweet with his revelation of the grace of God.
and as many precious promises that belong to believers.
As such, it sharply contrasted with his circumstances on
Patmos, Ireland.
In other words, when John read this, by the way, John was in exile.
He didn't have freedom.
He was an exile on the island Patmos.
David stated, the ordinances of the Lord are sure and altogether righteous.
They are more precious than gold than much pure gold.
They are sweeter than honey than honey from the comb.
Though the word is sweet to believers, it will be bitter
to unbelievers when it brings divine judgment on them.
So listen, church, we may look at the end times with anticipation, knowing
that we are on the winning side, but to the unbeliever,
This is the most bitter news that could ever come out, is
that Jesus is gonna return.
I don't know.
Do you remember when y'all, do you remember before Christ when you were lost?
Do you remember that that time in your life?
I do.
And I sat and I've said this before, but I've sat under
a preacher, man, he could preach Revelation.
I'm talking like he and it scare you.
And I remember it be Sunday nights.
I'm sure you remember Philip and listen, Sunday nights and we'd
be sitting there and he would be preaching this and literally
everything in my mind and body was like, get
me out of here.
I hate this.
Why?
Because I was scared.
I knew that this took place right then, I was lost and I had rejected Christ.
So it was bitter for me.
But, you know, ever since I given my life to Christ and been born again.
You know what?
No scripture is bitter.
It may hurt.
It may convict.
It may it may expose my my incorrect heart
posture, but it's sweet because all the reason
why God's word exposes and causes pain and
conviction in my spirit and in my heart is to turn me closer towards Christ.
That's a sweet reality for a believer.
So, why does God give this
break in between trumpets?
I do not know.
But it does tell us that the finished work of judgment is near.
And this brings us to the 2nd part of this break.
This part is much more well known and frequently debated.
We're going to read 14 versus this time.
Okay?
And so if you're okay with that, say, okay.
Revelation 11, yes.
Revelation 11, starting in verse one.
And there was given me a read, like unto a rod, and the angel
stood saying, rise and measure the temple of God and the altar.
And then that worship therein, but the court which is without the
temple, leave out, and measure it not, for it is given unto the
Gentiles, and the holy city shall they tread underfoot
40 and 2 months.
All right?
And I'll give power unto my 2 witnesses, and
they shall prophesy a 1,203 score days
clothed in sackcloth.
These are the two olive trees, and the two candlesticks standing
before the god of the earth.
And if any man will hurt them, fire proceedeth out of
their mouth, and devoureth their enemies, and if any man will hurt
them, he must, in this manner, be killed.
These have power to shut heaven, that if
it rain not in the days of their prophecy, and have power over waters,
to turn them to blood, and to smite the earth with all plagues,
as often as they will.
And when they shall have finished their testimony, the beast that
ascendeth out of the bottomless pit shall make war against them
and shall overcome them and kill them.
And their dead bodies shall lie in the street of
the great city, which spiritually is called Sodom and Egypt, where also
our Lord was crucified.
We're talking about Jerusalem here.
And they are the people and kindreds and tongues and nations shall see their
dead bodies 3 days and a half, and shall
not suffer the dead bodies be put into graze.
And they that dwell upon the earth shall rejoice over them and
make merry and shall send gifts one to another because these 2
prophets tormented them that dwelt on the earth.
And after 3 days and a half of the spirit of life from God entered
into them, the spirit of life from God entered into them, and
they stood upon their feet and great fear fell upon them which saw them,
they heard a great voice from heaven, saying unto them, come up hither.
And they ascended up to heaven in a cloud, and their enemies beheld them.
In the same hour, is there a great earthquake, and the 10th part of
the city fell, and then the earthquake was slain of men 7000,
and the remnant were affrighted, and gave glory to the God of heaven.
The 2nd wall was passed, and behold, the 3rd wall cometh quickly.
Wow.
What in the world is this, right?
See, God instructs John to measure the temple on the altar, but
not the outside courts.
In other words, the outside courts at that time was known as like the court of the Gentiles.
It was not, it was not what we would call the holy of holies.
And so, and so we see here that God is telling John to
measure the holy of holies, and really what
that would entail is, is that the holy of holies is God's.
Right, in that time, you would measure something for ownership, right?
It'd be kind of like, you know, I don't know if y'all know, but if
you have like a property line, it's a big deal, right?
If there's a property line issue, you got an issue.
You see what I'm saying?
You measure property lines because it tells who owns what and who doesn't own what.
Well, right here, that's the symbolic of God
said, I own the holy of holies, but don't measure the
courts outside because we
see that the Gentile is going to trample over them.
Now, what does that mean?
We can be assured of one thing.
At some point, the sacrifices and offerings will stop being given.
This will be the time that we know of, that the beast, the Antichrist
stops all of it, makes the people worship and give offerings to him instead.
I believe this 42 months period is referring to the second
half of the 7 years.
During this time, the Gentile nations will trample over the holy city.
This signifies a desecration of holy things.
During this time.
God is going to give two witnesses the authority to prophesy.
They have the ability to protect themselves with fire,
and they will be able to do much and many miracles.
But at some point, the beast comes up and kills them,
and their dead bodies lay up on
the streets of Jerusalem for three and a half days.
I noticed this, people were celebrating their death.
Again, in verse 10, and those who dwell on the earth will rejoice over them and
celebrate, and they will send gifts to one another because these 2
prophets torment those who dwell on the earth.
You say, how in the world could that happen?
Well, we've seen it happen in our society.
People that fear the Lord be killed and it be celebrated.
As a matter of fact, if I'm not mistaken, we're nearing
or at a year, when Charlie Kirk got assassinated
and people literally lined the streets in celebration of him
getting shot in the neck and killed.
So this should not, this should not surprise us.
In foreign countries right now, when they have mass murders of Christians, they celebrate these things.
You see what I'm saying?
Listen, society is backwards already.
It's not going to be come backwards.
It's already backwards.
But then all of a sudden they were resurrected.
Could you imagine that?
They get killed, they're thinking, man, look at these dead people.
Really, that's what they did to Jesus.
Amen.
Revelation 11, 11 through 12, but after these 3.5 days, the breath
of life from God came unto them, they stood on their feet and
great fear fell upon those who were watching them.
I'd be scared too.
Hey man, if I was making fun of someone who was dead, they just started walking.
And they heard a loud voice from heaven saying to them, come up hither.
They went up into the heaven in a cloud.
And their enemies watched them.
Now, we see, right after that, God sent a great earthquake
making a 10th of the city fall, and 7,000 people died.
This obviously sets up the 3rd wall, which is the 7th trumpet.
Now, what do we need to know about these two witnesses?
The speculations of who they are can be quite interesting.
There's really two main thoughts of who these two witnesses are.
A popular pairing is Moses and Elijah.
Right?
If you look at, you know, Elijah had a chariot
of fire, that he left, man, and Moses.
He brought plagues upon Egypt,
so there's a lot of different symbolism and different similarities
between what they did and their ministries here on earth and what these
2 witnesses are going to do.
So you could have Moses and Elijah.
Also, these are the 2 men who came down to the amount of transfigurations,
so God has already used them in a certain way like this.
Others have said, not Moses, but Elijah
and Enoch, the only two people that we have recorded to not die.
Right?
Elijah was taken up in the chariot of fire and then we see Enoch where he was, then he wasn't.
He was translated.
He didn't die.
And so it could be those two.
Now, we may never know who these two witnesses will be,
but we do get some description of what they symbolize.
In verse 4 says, these are the two olive trees and the two lampstands
that stand before the Lord of the Earth.
Now, if you reference this, it's referring to the Old
Testament text, Zachariah chapter 4, verse
2 through 14, the 2 witnesses in that passage were
Joshua the high priest and Zerobabble, the governor.
Their connection to the lampstands, they were empowered
by the Holy Spirit symbolized by the olive oil.
In other words, these 2 witnesses in Revelation 11 are
empowered by the Holy Spirit to do the work of God for an allotted time.
Like prophets of old, these 2 witnesses will
be able to do supernatural miracles.
The fire will destroy those who will try to harm them.
Like Elijah, they would have power to stop rain,
have power like Moses to turn water into blood and
to bring on plagues in the midst of their of the unbelief,
apostasy and satanic power, the great tribulation.
These 2 witnesses will be a threat to the entire wicked world for
a literal period of 1,260 days.
Now, there's another view,
remember, a lot of a lot of the argument and revelation is, is
it symbolic, or is it literal?
Right?
So, in other words, is it just symbolizing something, or is it really saying what it's saying?
Uh, could these two witnesses not be two actual
people, but rather be symbolic of the church?
Think about it.
The church is empowered by the Holy Spirit.
Amen?
Or at least we should be.
If you're saved, you are.
Um, the church has the ability to do wondrous things in the name of Jesus.
The church will be persecuted and killed by those who oppose God.
Here then, if we look at it in this way,
it's not necessarily, I believe that it is 2
actual people, witnesses that God sends.
But if you look at the principles of this particular viewpoint,
it's really powerful for us today.
Here then is a wonderful word for churches of every generation.
It's not just the end time churches that should be penitent and proclaim
God's word against sin.
It's not just the end time churches, it must minister during times of suffering.
Nor is it just the end time churches that must be empowered by the Spirit.
No, these are for Christians for all times.
No wonder when John received the word, it tasted as sweet as honey.
In verses 5 through 6, John ascribes the effective ministry of
the end time churches, this is someone who believes in the symbolic,
but I take the principles of this, and we can apply it to ourselves today.
The outcome is symbolize as fire from the mouths.
The word of God and the word of God and judgment from his prophets was
likened to fire in the Old Testament.
Therefore, this is what the Lord God Almighty says because the people have spoken these words.
I'll make my words in your mouth, a fire and these people, the wood it consumes.
Jeremiah 5.14 further, these churches are
just as mighty as the fire belching demonic minions described in
chapter 9.
What this view teaches is, although I don't
necessarily agree that the 2 witnesses are symbolic of the church.
It is a beautiful similarity of how the church should minister today.
We can look at the ministry of these 2 witnesses that were full of the Holy Spirit.
They fire came out of their mouth.
They could work, they could work on all the things.
We can see that in a church today as well.
Although, um, It's just principle
and truth, we can gather how we are to operate.
Church, we have the power of the Holy Spirit.
We are on the winning side of this.
We are to operate from victory rather than for victory.
Too many of us are fighting for victory.
The way we're fighting this battle is we're like, I got to get there, I got to get there.
Listen, if you have Jesus, you are already there.
You're fighting from victory.
So we, listen, the church should be, the church is,
the most powerful force in the world right now.
Do you realize that?
Devil's done a good job at making us not feel like it.
Not realize it.
But God's word is very clear.
Is that his plan for us, for this world to be delivered?
is through his son Jesus, but we are ambassadors of Christ.
And so as we look to the end here, you know,
how we operated now, how are you operating in your life?
Do you share the word of God in such a way that it's like a fire?
It consumes those who you speak to.
I'm not saying consumed like Q.
consumes their spirit, consumes their heart and soul.
Listen, when I preach, I want the word of God to consume the people.
To completely overwhelm them in a way that it turns
them to the almighty God, That should be our goal, all of our goals.
So how do you operate?
When head's bad eyes closed before we get into our prayer time.